NARRATOR: Horses frightened the Arawaks
when they first saw them,
for they believed them
to be giant dogs that fed on human flesh.
But over time, Native Americans
came to use the horse
for their own purposes.
These dancers of the North American plains
lived by hunting buffalo.
But stalking the buffalo on foot
was a slow and dangerous affair.
Horses revolutionized the hunt.
What once took days now took moments.
But in time, the buffalo of
the plains were replaced
by European cattle.
With them, a new culture
evolved, that of the cowboy.
The all-American rodeo is
actually anything but.
The bucking bronco, the branded
cattle, even the word "rodeo"
are foreigners, all Spanish imports.